[The Heir]
[Episode 16]
Miss Li Zhen.
Lord Yan has a letter for you.
The medicinal ink treatment
might be worth a try,
but the key to this matter
is Xianglan's consent.
Whether my daughter
can be persuaded to agree
is up to you, Miss Li Zhen.
What do you think, Miss Li Zhen?
Please lead the way.
This way, please.
Miss Yan.
Using petals as decoration,
though the wound hasn't healed yet,
it looks beautiful.
Man.
My Lady, look.
How is it?
How did you come up with this idea?
I heard that
once in ancient times,
an emperor's concubine
accidentally hit her cheek
against a crystal screen,
leaving a rather large scar.
Unexpectedly, after the emperor saw it,
he thought the scar
enhanced the concubine's beauty.
So, the women in the palace followed suit,
smearing cinnabar
and rouge on their cheeks
to imitate the look
of a scar or bloodstain,
creating a unique charm.
Later, people named
this makeup technique "Slanted Red."
What you have today, Miss Yan,
surpasses what "Slanted Red" is!
Exactly.
My Lady's beauty
is unmatched in the world.
Right, My Lady?
Don't make fun of me.
Man is right.
Miss Yan.
Don't belittle yourself.
You are very beautiful.
You haven't had a good look around
since you arrived in Huizhou, right?
No.
If you are free today,
shall I take you out for a spin?
Really?
Sure!
Let's go!
All right!
Today is the happiest I've been
since I came to Huizhou.
Even when I was in the Capital,
I have never been this happy.
Li Zhen,
thank you.
If you like it, Miss Yan,
I will take you around more next time.
No one
really wants to spend their whole life
living with a veil.
I recently heard that
when you were in the Capital,
you actively sought medical advice.
Why, after coming to Huizhou,
did you refuse to get treated?
If I'm not mistaken,
you did all that
for the sake of Lord Yan,
your father, right?
What are you trying to say?
You are afraid
that your illness
will become a burden to him,
and that your father will be deceived
by people with ulterior motives.
You are even more afraid that some people,
once they can manipulate your illness,
they can hold it against your father.
Instead of letting him
spend too much time on it and worrying,
it's better not to treat it,
right?
Li Zhen,
you are indeed different
from those who flatter
and pander.
I like it.
My illness
cannot be cured.
So I just want
my father to focus,
be a good official,
regain the emperor's favor early,
and return to the Capital.
Have you told your father
this before?
What's the use of saying it?
If there is any chance of a cure,
my father wouldn't let it go.
It will only cause sadness.
Better not to say it.
Miss Yan.
Originally, this time,
I wanted to change your mind.
But after hearing what you just said,
I don't think your condition
can be cured by this ink alone.
As expected.
You think so, too.
The hardest thing to cure in this world
is this.
If the heart cannot be healed,
everything else is in vain.
You and the people who care about you
will still torture each other—
this is the real dead end.
Take this ink stick first.
When you have thought it through,
come find me again.
Xianglan.
I found so many doctors for you,
and you've been through
so many treatments,
but they were all to no avail.
The more things like this happen,
the more anxious I get.
I'm afraid that one day,
when I am no longer in this world,
there won't be anyone
guarding you and protecting you like me.
The hardest thing to cure in this world
is this.
If the heart cannot be healed,
everything else is in vain.
You and the people who care about you
will still torture each other—
this is the real dead end.
Man.
Tell Father
to invite
Ms. Li Zhen to our residence tomorrow.
Miss Yan.
Today is the last day of the treatment.
Let's see
if the facial sores have healed.
Are you ready?
Wait a moment.
Lord Yan.
How about you
take off the cloth
for Miss Yan?
Dear.
Don't be afraid.
Zhen, you do it.
Lord Yan, you should do it.
No, you do it.
You do it.
You do it—
Dear,
let me see your face.
It's healed!
It's healed...
Look,
my daughter's face is healed, isn't it?
Look, dear.
It's healed.
It's healed!
It's healed, Father!
It's healed.
Thank you, Father.
Ms. Li Zhen.
I really don't know how to thank you.
Lord Yan, you're welcome.
It's what I should do.
The healing effect
of your Nine-Treasure Ink
is truly remarkable.
Zhen,
thank you!
Don't cry.
If you keep crying,
you won't be pretty anymore.
I'll stop crying.
Thank you!
[Li Jingfu]
Jingfu,
this is the medicinal ink
made by Zhen.
Look.
It's even better than
what you made back then.
Father,
for the medicinal ink,
Mother took me into the mountains.
She told me a lot
about what happened
between you two back then.
I originally thought
you were only focused on making ink
and were clumsy with words—
not one to say anything romantic.
But I didn't expect
that you had already expressed
your deep affection
to Mother long ago.
Silly child,
what do you know?
Let me tell you.
Your father was terrible with his words.
If he really knew how to be romantic,
would I complain about him every day?
Mother, do you know
what the Matchmaker Herb
I was looking for is?
Who knows what that is?
I asked you several times,
but you just wouldn't tell me.
This is the Matchmaker Herb
I was looking for.
Isn't this
the Red Phoenix Variegated Herb
I used for the medicine I applied
to your father?
Yes.
Dad clearly knew
it was called Red Phoenix Variegated Herb,
but still called it Matchmaker Herb
in his notes.
That's because this little herb
is the matchmaker that witnessed
your meeting.
You're such a fool.
Why didn't you...
tell me these things back then?
Look at you.
Now you don't even have the chance
to say it.
Who says there's no chance?
Mother, what Father didn't get to say,
I will say it for him.
What Father didn't finish doing,
I will continue doing it for him.
From now on,
the New Li's Ink Workshop
will be the hope of our family.
I'll work hard to make the ink I want.
I want to support our family
with my own abilities.
I want our family to be
happy.
Jingfu,
look at your daughter.
She's so sweet with her words.
You really should learn from her.
Mother,
this piece of ink was called
Nine-Treasure Ink
by the Li family's ancestors.
But since I won't return
to the main family,
there's no need to call it
by its original name
and cause misunderstandings.
You told me before
that Father used to say
he wanted to use your name
to name a piece of ink he made.
Although Father is no longer here,
the ink I make
is just like the ink Father made.
I will be naming this ink
Fu Jin Ink
to commemorate the love
between you and Father.
Fu Jin Ink.
Jingfu.
Look.
This is the ink
our daughter made for us.
[House of New Li's Ink]
Miss Li Zhen, how is it?
A... A little bit more to the right.
More to the right?
Right, right.
Miss Li Zhen,
is it even now?
No. This needs to be a little higher.
A little higher?
All right.
-How about now?
-The flower has to go a little higher.
A little higher?
Like this?
Yes, yes.
Ronghua!
Why are you here?
I brought you some good stuff.
Come in.
How about this?
Yes! Hang it up first.
Ronghua, why did you
carry this all the way here by yourself?
It's so heavy.
Put it down. Let me see.
New Li's Ink Workshop is opening soon.
I was going to
send you an invitation later,
and here you are.
This is great.
It's great.
Zhen,
if only one day
I could be like you,
free to do what I want,
how wonderful that would be.
As long as you want to,
you can do it anytime.
Ronghua, my shop is short of hands.
Do you want to come
and help me?
You're daydreaming again.
With my father and brother around,
it's hard for me
to even step into this shop.
I brought you a lot of good stuff today.
What is it?
I can't help you out,
but I have prepared everything you need.
Look.
This is an abacus made of agate.
It's not as precious as fragrant rosewood,
but it's durable.
This is what I usually use.
This account book, too.
I had it custom-made.
It's better than those sold on the market.
And this.
I specifically asked my mother
to buy ejiao from Dong'exian.
New Li's Ink Workshop is opening soon.
It'll be tough on you.
You must remember
to take care of yourself.
Only when you are healthy,
can everything go smoothly.
This wooden box, too.
You can use it to
keep money and account books.
I got you a lock too. Look.
Ronghua.
Thank you.
If you stand on ceremony with me,
I will get angry.
Of course not.
I will accept all of these!
If any of them break in the future,
I'll have to come find you,
my Goddess of Wealth.
If you would like something,
I wouldn't dare disobey.
This is great, Zhen.
Ronghua, I'll show you around.
Here, put it down.
This way.
Okay.
I did it all myself.
This is...
I once said,
once New Li's Ink Workshop
is ready,
I will personally visit
to discuss with Master Qi
and invite you to invest in it.
[Contract]
Five hundred taels.
This amount is...
Don't worry, Master Qi.
Let me calculate it for you.
We have hundreds of medicinal inks now.
Even before it is finished,
half of it has already been ordered.
At the price of three taels of silver,
even before the medicinal ink
is completely sold out,
you'd already break even.
Moreover, on the opening day,
I have invited Lord Yan to be present.
With him there,
I'm sure I can sell another 100 orders
of medicinal ink.
If you're not convinced,
you can ask the other banks in the city.
With my conditions,
I bet no one would refuse.
If you have no objections,
let's talk about the profit distribution.
Miss Li Zhen,
I'll keep this contract
for now.
But if you want those five hundred taels,
you have to meet someone first.
Madam, Miss Li Zhen has arrived.
Miss Li Zhen, please.
Miss Li Zhen, please take a seat.
Miss Li Zhen, do you know who I am?
Cuiqiao Cottage's Madam Wang.
[Madam (Da Gu): a polite way
to address ladies in ancient times.]
Everyone in Huizhou knows you.
Opening an ink workshop and becoming
a manager at such a young age—
Miss Li Zhen,
you are indeed extraordinary.
Madam Wang, you invited me here
because of Master Qi's
investment in New Li's Ink Workshop,
right?
You are straightforward and frank, Miss.
I have one thing to ask.
It's difficult for a woman
to tread through the world of business.
Doing ink for Li Ink quietly
could've been a good choice.
Why did you choose the difficult path
of opening your own ink workshop?
Madam Wang, your business reputation
resonates throughout the Nine Provinces.
Once upon a time,
you must have made the same choice
as I did.
May I ask—
have you ever regretted that choice?
You are indeed quick-witted, Miss.
Have some tea.
Madam, the tea merchants have arrived.
Please go over and appraise the tea.
Since Miss Li Zhen is also here,
why not help
with choosing the tea?
I don't know much about tea.
How could I dare
to decide this for Madam Wang?
It doesn't matter. Just follow your heart.
All right then, I shall have a go.
Madam Wang is here.
-Hello, Madam Wang.
Today, Miss Li Zhen
will select the tea for me.
All right!
Whose tea is this?
This is West Lake Longjing.
The leaves are yellow-green and glossy
with a strong aroma.
It is the top choice for literati
to entertain guests.
This is Dongting Bi Luo Chun—
also known as "Astoundingly Fragrant."
It has a silver-green color,
and overflows with fragrance
after brewing.
Junshan Silver Needle.
This is a yellow tea,
with an orange-yellow core.
It's also known as...
That's enough.
I got it.
Thank you.
Miss.
This is Yunnan's Pu'er.
It comes from the same source
as a tribute tea.
Pu'er?
Good tea.
Sir, compared to other teas,
this tea of yours is not as refined.
What kind of tea is it?
Miss,
this is Wild Tea from Houkeng.
Wild tea?
Houkeng?
if my memory serves me right,
it's in Taipingxian, Ningguofu, right?
Exactly.
Miss, although this is a Wild Tea
and looks ordinary,
after brewing,
it has a strong orchid fragrance
and a sweet, mellow taste.
Have a taste, it's very delicious.
This is the good tea you chose?
Yes, this is the one.
There were so many good teas
to choose from,
why did you pick
this ordinary Wild Tea?
I only know how to make ink,
yet you asked me to appraise tea today.
At the end of the day,
it's a test of
my vision and knowledge,
isn't it?
Then tell me,
why did you choose this Wild Tea?
In business, profit comes first.
Making money
is naturally the most important.
So I think
it doesn't matter
if the 5 types of tea today
is good or bad.
What's important is
I know this Houkeng Wild Tea
has a unique advantage.
What may that be?
It originates from Houkeng.
Houkeng is at the northern foot
of Mount Huangshan,
close to Huizhou.
It was also brought here
by the village head himself.
Buying from the source leaves more profit.
Just like those ink merchants—
it's the same principle as why
they have to travel a long way to Huizhou
if they want to buy Hui Ink.
I think it's the same for tea and ink.
Before being polished,
they look ordinary.
Once polished, they are extraordinary.
And the village head told me
this tea has an orchid scent.
If pressed into the shape of an orchid,
its appearance will surely be
a hundred times better than now,
and the profit goes without saying.
Miss Li Zhen, you have good judgment.
I will have someone deliver
the 500 taels of silver
for New Li's ink workshop
to your residence.
Thank you, Madam Wang.
Sister, how was it?
I really like this Miss Li Zhen.
I have already sent
the 500 taels of silver on your behalf.
I asked you to come here
because there is another urgent matter.
I have found the Gao Kun
you asked me to look for.
He is now in Xu Village on Mount Jinlong.
This Gao Kun
is indeed Zhao Shen's confidant.
Catching him will definitely bring down
Zhao Shen and the Tian family.
Lord Yan.
Zhen, congratulations.
Thank you, Lord Yan!
Greetings, Lord Yan.
Lord Yan!
You look well.
Thank you for the compliment.
Lord Yan.
You were at the completion
of the ancient lacquer-soot ink
to see things through
from beginning to end.
This is just a small ink workshop opening.
To have Lord Yan come in person—
what an honor
to Zhen!
You flatter me!
You flatter me.
Lord Yan.
Since you are here today,
I wonder if you can write a calligraphy
for New Li's Ink Workshop
to be passed down to future generations?
Zhen, to be honest,
I was just... thinking the same thing!
Great!
Zhen.
This is such a grand opening,
but you don't have much ink in stock.
What if too many people come
and you can't supply enough ink?
What should we do then?
Mother, don't worry.
I know what I'm doing.
Zhen.
Fu Jin Ink!
Bravo!
-Bravo!
I'm embarrassing myself.
Official Fan has arrived.
Official Fan?
Official Fan, you're here.
Official Fan!
Miss Li Zhen.
Official Fan.
Qi Jiu couldn't come himself,
so he insisted I come to congratulate
Miss Li Zhen for him.
Thank you.
Since Lord Yan personally wrote
the calligraphy for Fu Jin Ink,
even if the stock is not fully ready,
I would like to order 100 sticks
to add some joy
to New Li's Ink Workshop's opening.
What do you think, Miss Li?
Certainly!
If you are willing
to take only 40 sticks first,
I am willing to give
a 30% discount,
for the remaining 60 sticks. How's that?
Of course!
Good!
Since you are willing to give a discount,
I'll purchase another 50 sticks.
Great!
Since Official Fan has spoken,
I'll order another 50!
Thank you.
I'll add 50 more too!
Thank you, everyone.
Miss Li Zhen.
It is time.
Let's open for business.
All right!
New Li's Ink Workshop
is officially open!
-Great!
[House of New Li's Ink]
Zhen.
There were many guests
at the ink workshop's opening today.
I saw you were extremely busy,
so I didn't pass you
this congratulatory gift.
What is this?
Open it and see for yourself.
This inkstone has a fine texture.
It works best with medicinal ink.
Who gave this?
[For my granddaughter, Li Zhen]
[Fu Jin Ink]
You made it.
You actually...
You actually made it.
You made it.
Third Brother.
How are you still
in the mood to drink here?
Tell me.
We went through so much trouble
putting up all sorts of obstacles.
But Li Zhen
still managed to establish
New Li's Ink Workshop.
Not only that,
she also created
some kind of medicinal ink.
I heard that for today's opening,
the Ink Affairs Official and his daughter
both went in person to back her up.
Who does she think she is?
Third Brother, I'm asking you.
Why didn't you go stop
New Li's Ink Workshop's opening today?
We should've sent someone
to smash her shop.
Smash her shop?
On what grounds should we smash her shop?
Did she use your pine soot
or your glue?
You took back the old ink workshop.
That's because it belongs to our family—
perfectly justifiable.
But what right do you have
to New Li's Ink Workshop?
The recipe is her own.
The staff are her own.
She didn't even use
her own grandfather's help.
You want to smash her shop?
Am I some bully or bandit?
Third Brother,
how much have you had to drink?
You...
You're speaking up for her?
Hey, what is this?
[To Uncle Jingdong,
Invitation to New Li's Ink Workshop's opening]
This is that medicinal ink?
Li Zhen is so bold.
How dare she send ink here to provoke us!
Who said she sent it?
I...
I bought this ink...
for 3 times the price
from an ink merchant.
I just wanted to see
if Li Zhen could really create
the Nine-Treasure Medicinal Ink.
She did.
Have you lost your mind?
She did...
She really did.
You really have lost your mind.
It's just a piece of medicinal ink.
So what?
I'll tell you what.
I, Li Jingdong,
have made ink my whole life,
but I can't make this piece of ink.
So what?
So...
Go.
Leave.
Let me be alone for a while.
Go.
Third Brother.
I'm making it clear today.
If you tolerate her,
you're raising a threat yourself.
Today, she sends the invitation here
showing off.
Soon enough,
New Li will take over the main Li.
The family temple, ancestral hall,
and ink workshop
will all change their names
but not their surname.
Then the Li family
will be the biggest joke
in Huizhou ever.
Don't you regret it.
No...
It's truly ridiculous.
A woman
opened an ink workshop?
What a disgrace to Hui Ink.
Right.
She is also promoting some medicinal ink
called Nine-Treasure something
as her signature.
I heard from others
that this ink
has been lost for over a century.
I don't believe she can create it.
It must be a fake.
Wh-Why don't I get someone
to buy a few pieces,
and claim it ruined their health?
That will surely ruin
New Li's Ink Workshop.
It's just a small ink workshop.
You don't have to bother.
These days,
Lord Yan has been looking after Li Zhen
because she cured
Miss Yan's chronic illness.
If you go now,
you might just bring trouble
upon yourself.
I'll have someone else go.
Master.
A letter has arrived from the Capital.
Great!
This is truly joyous news
for our Tian family.
Master, what joyous news is it?
I've found our daughter
an excellent match in the Capital.
Really?
I was just worrying
about Ronghua's marriage.
This is wonderful.
Whose son is it?
He is the grandson of
Lord Xu from the Capital.
As far as I know,
this Lord Xu
dotes on his only daughter
very much.
Lord Xu?
If our Tian family
can secure this marriage,
we'll have a backer in the Capital.
In the future,
it will be of great benefit
to our Tian Ink.
Our Tian Ink will be able to thrive.
Then... Then, when I go out drinking,
won't everyone
have to defer to me?
Just thinking about it feels great.
Father.
Lord Xu is no ordinary man.
Would such a prominent family
really be willing to marry someone
from a merchant family like ours?
Brother, what a party pooper you are.
What's wrong with our family?
Since ancient times,
officials and merchants are distinct.
The divide is as deep as a chasm.
If you don't understand, shut up.
Master.
Chang is right.
How could a family like that
take a fancy to us?
It's not about whether they fancy us,
it's whether we fancy them.
Rumor has it
that when this child was young, a fever
damaged his brain.
That's why
he's still not engaged at this age.
This is also why we have
the chance to secure this marriage.
Master, he has a damaged brain?
Then he's a fool!
I don't think
it's that serious.
Then again,
if there's nothing wrong with this child,
such a good thing
would never fall into the lap
of our Tian family.
No way!
Father, I won't marry him!
You already treated me
like an object once.
Are you going to
repeat the same mistake today
and do it to me a second time?
What nonsense!
Is this
the same as last time?
Do you know how much money
and effort I've spent
for this marriage?
For the honor of our Tian family,
you will marry him
whether you
want to or not.
Master.
Please don't get mad.
Can we take our time to discuss this?
Discuss what?
What a bunch of useless fools.
There's no need to discuss this.
My word is final.
Chang.
Sheng.
You two stay at home
and keep a close eye on your sister.
Don't let her run around.
Just stay at home
and stop letting
your imagination run wild.
Once we get word from the Capital,
we'll leave
and you'll get married right away.
Master.
You...
Is Master back?
Where is he?
Inside.
Master!
You're injured.
I'll go get some medicine.
Rouge ink.
Just apply this.
Gao Kun is very cunning.
It took a lot of effort to catch him.
He's locked up now.
By the way, Master,
you weren't at
the House of New Li's Ink's opening.
Miss Li Zhen should be there right now.
It's not far away.
How about we go take a look?
No need.
Business first.
[Huizhou Prefecture Office]
Master Qi, what brings you here
for a visit?
Lord He.
Sorry to bother you.
Please take a look at these.
[Magistrate of Huizhou,
He Wenchang]
[Account Ledger of Revenues
and Expenditures of Shexian Prefecture]
Master Qi,
what are you trying to say
showing me this?
Lord He,
you've just arrived in Huizhou,
so you might not be fully aware
of the situation.
Zhao Shen, Magistrate Zhao,
has been taking bribes for years.
He abuses his power
and oppresses the locals.
Every single detail is recorded here.
Please judge wisely.
This is no small matter.
Master Qi, you must act with caution.
Handling a case requires evidence—
both witnesses and material evidence.
If we only rely on these account books,
I'm afraid they might
be suspected of forgery.
Lord He, given your position,
it's perfectly normal
for you to have concerns.
But please rest assured, My Lord.
Besides this evidence,
the confidants who helped Zhao Shen
have also been captured by us.
What?
You...
You are just a merchant.
How can you act on behalf of His Majesty?
Qi Jiu,
your actions are truly a transgression.